BABY DORY: Hi. I'm Dory.
I suffer from
short-term remembory loss.
- Yes!
- That's exactly what you say!
Okay, okay.
We'll pretend to be the other kids now.
- (JENNY INHALES DEEPLY)
- (CHARLIE CLEARS THROAT)
- (GASPS) Hi, Dory!
- Ahoy there!
- (LAUGHING)
- Do you want to play hide-and-seek?
Okay. I love-- Okay.
We'll hide
and you count and come find us.
Okay, Daddy.
No, not Daddy. I'm the nice fish
who wants to be your friend, okay?
- Okay, Daddy.
- No.
- I'm hiding.
- Now count to ten.
One, two, three...
Um, four...
Um...
I like sand. Sand is squishy.
- (FISH LAUGHING PLAYFULLY)
- Mommy, can I go play with them?
- Dory. Dory. Dory, honey.
- Dory. Kelpcake.
Undertow, sweetie.
Remember, honey, we have to
stay away from the undertow.
Okay, sweetheart,
what about that rhyme we learned?
♪ We see the undertow and we say...
♪ Let's go
No. It's, "Heck no."
Okay? Let's try it again.
♪ We see the undertow and we say...
♪ There's the undertow!
♪ There's the undertow
There is the undertow
♪ Hey, you found the undertow
And we see the undertow ♪
- Did I forget again?
- No, no. No.
- No, sweetie. Don't worry about it.
- No biggie, kelpcake.
What if I forget you?
(GASPS) Would you ever forget me?
- (GASPS)
- Oh, kelpcake, no.
We will never forget you, Dory.
And we know you'll never forget us.
BABY DORY: Hello?
Hello!
- Did you hear that?
- What's that? Hear what?
- Stan, I just heard someone say hello.
- I didn't hear anybody say hello.
I don't know, Stan.
I just heard someone say hello.
There's a lot of fish here.
Anybody could have just said hello.
- BABY DORY: Hello?
- There.
- STAN: Where?
- There. There. Right there.
- Where am I looking?
- There!
- Oh.
- Hello!
- BABY DORY: Hello?
- Oh my goodness, it's a child!
- STAN: Hi, kid. Over here. Hello?
- Hello? Hi.
Hi. I'm Dory. Can you please help me?
Hi, Dory. Are you lost?
- Yeah, where are your parents?
- Um...
I can't remember.
- Oh.
- Well we'll look around.
Are any of these fish your parents?
Hi, I'm Dory. Can you please help me?
- What?
- Um...
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
- Honey, you just said that.
- Mmm.
- I did?
- Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry. I suffer from
short-term remembory loss.
- Oh, how awful.
- Short-term memory loss?
Okay, you wait here for one second.
Okay, sweetie pie?
- Stan. Stan. Stan.
- What? What?
What do we do? The poor thing is lost!
- What do you want me to do?
- We have to do something.
- She can't remember a thing!
- She could come from anywhere.
Wow, you are no help today.
Dory? Sweetie? How about we--
She's gone.
Well, that's not good. Hey, Dory!
- Dory!
I'm Dory. I lost my family.
Can you help me?
I'm Dory. I suffer from
short-term memory-- (GASPS)
♪ Just keep swimming
Just keep swimming
Swimming What do we do? ♪
Hi. I lost my family. Can you help me?
Where did you see them last?
Well, uh, funny story, but I forgot.
Oh, sweetie,
do you want to come swim with us?
That is the nicest offer
I've gotten all day.
I think. Uh, I can't remember.
Anyhoo, thanks, (CHUCKLES)
but I'm looking for someone.
(SIGHS)
Oh. Can't remember. Can't remember.
Can't remember.
- Hi! I'm Dory.
- (FISH GASP)
Was it something I said?
Kidding. Okay, you're not coming back.
I was looking for something and I--
Okay, get it. Date night. Have fun.
Well, I hope you find whatever it is
you're looking for.
You and me both.
Any idea what that was?
I'm sorry.
Okay. Guess we'll hang out another
time. Don't be a stranger, Stranger.
Huh?
MARLIN: A white boat!
They took my son!
- My son! Help me! Please!
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- Watch out!
- (BOTH SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
Oh! Oh, sorry! Are you okay?
- He's gone. He's gone.
- There, there.
- No, he's gone.
- It's all right.
- He's gone.
- It'll be okay.
No, no, they took him away.
I have to find the boat.
A boat? Hey, I've seen a boat!
- You have?
- Uh-huh.
It went this way! Follow me!
Thank you! Thank you.
Thank you so much!
(SNORING)
Klaus. Klaus, the pinata's drooping.
Hand me the ratchet wrench.
I can fix it. Ow!
Hey, Marlin?
(MARLIN SNORING)
Oh. Hey, guys, I was just--
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Dory! It's not time to get up yet.
You have to go back to bed.
And remember, the anemone stings.
Oh right. Yeah. Sorry.
Back to bed, back to bed.
Hey, Marlin? Ow!
Back to bed! That was it.
Very simple. Bed. Back to it.
DORY: Mmm, got it.
Hey, Marlin?
And we're up. That's it.
Ready to start the day.
- And we were looking for something.
- Nemo.
Right. I remember it
like it was yesterday.
Of course, I don't really remember
yesterday all that well.
(NEMO LAUGHING)
Anyway, I would say the scariest
moment of the trip was the 4 sharks.
NEMO: Wait, I thought
there were 3 sharks.
MARLIN: No. No,
there were definitely four.
But last time you told it,
there were three.
Son, which one of us travelled
across the entire ocean?
- Nemo did.
- (YELPS)
Obviously we had to cross the ocean...
to find him, so you know... He went first.
I guess that's true. Isn't it?
Well, you made it!
You almost missed the field trip.
A field trip? Ooh, I love field trips.
Where are we going?
- I thought you told her.
- I did tell her!
- Uh... Dory.
- Yeah.
Mr Ray has too many fish
to keep an eye on today.
Uh-huh.
So it would be best if today
you weren't exactly with the class.
Oh. Why not?
Well, you know, you have problems
remembering things sometimes.
That's the one thing I can remember.
Yes.
Okay. And sometimes it's not your fault,
but it can cause you to wander.
And Mr Ray doesn't really have time
to worry about fish who wander.
In other words,
he doesn't have enough help.
Poor guy.
You know, he's so overworked.
- You understand.
- I totally understand now.
- Okay.
- Mm-hmm.
He wants me
to be the teacher's assistant.
Uh... No, not exactly.
I am so honoured. I have never been
a teaching assistant before.
Mr Ray! You got help.
(LAUGHS AWKWARDLY)
Oh. Okeydokey.
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
- All right, kids.
- Today's the day!
Our field trip to the sting ray migration.
Sting ray migration.
Now, does anyone know
why we migrate?
(COUGHS)
Come on. You got to know this stuff.
Migration is about going back to...
- Bed!
- Yes!
- No.
- The sand!
- No! Migration is about going home.
- Home.
- Which is where you're from.
Where you're from.
Can someone tell me
where they're from?
- I live by a giant rock.
- I live 3 coral caves away from here.
My house is covered in algae.
Where'd you grow up, Dory?
Me? Um, I don't know.
My family. Where are they?
- Can I help you?
- (STUDENTS LAUGHING)
I'm sorry. Did I forget again?
You see, I suffer from--
STUDENTS: Short-term memory loss.
How can you remember your family
if you have short-term memory loss?
Good question. See, I can remember
some things because well...
They make sense.
Like, um, I have a family.
I know because I've-- I must have
come from somewhere. Right?
Everyone has a family.
I may not remember their names
and what they look like.
And I may not even be able to
ever find them again, but, um...
- What were we talking about?
- Mommies and daddies.
Mommies and daddies. Right.
Why are we talking about
mommies and daddies? Oh. Oh!
That class. Uh-oh. Why me? Okay.
You guys seem a little young,
but, um, okay.
You see, kids,
when two fish love each other--
And we'll stop right there.
Climb aboard, explorers.
I feel a migration song coming on.
Oh...
♪ Migration, migration
let's learn about migration
♪ It's nature's inspiration
to move around the sea
♪ Here's a scientific promise
That a fish who's Oceanodromous
♪ Where did everyone go? I'm by myself
Oh there they are. I'm back
♪ Plus or minus 4 degrees
based on solar positioning ♪
Oh, kids stay away from the edge.
Okay, you hear that? Okay, everybody
stay back from the edge. Come on.
- Okay, that's too far.
- That's too far.
Come on. Come on.
Get back over here. Back this way.
- Now, I need everyone to listen to me.
- All right, listen up!
- When the rays pass through here--
- The rays, gonna pass through.
What do we have to be careful of?
Everybody has to be careful of what?
Hmm?
ALL: The undertow!
MR RAY: That's right.
That's right. The under-- The undertow?
MR RAY: Because the current created
by all the flapping is very strong.
And if you're not careful,
you can get pulled into--
Mr Ray! So how do the stingrays
all know where to go?
That's what an instinct is, Nemo.
Something deep inside you that feels
so familiar that you have to listen to it.
Like a song you've always known.
And I can hear mine now!
STINGRAYS: ♪ To and fro,
our hearts know where to go
♪ Beating like a drum
it sends us back to where we're from
♪ Oh... we're going home
- ♪ We know who we are...
- (STUDENTS GASPING)
♪ And it's time to travel far
♪ For days and nights we'll roam,
to make our way back home
♪ Oh... we're going home
- ♪ Swimming to and fro,
- Wow!
♪ Our hearts know where to go
♪ Beating like a drum, it sends us back
to where we're from ♪
We see the undertow
and we say-- (SCREAMS)
- ALL: Dory!
- (SCREAMING)
Dory!
MR RAY: Dory! Dory!
- (GASPS) Is she dead?
- MR RAY: No, she's not dead.
- STUDENTS: Aw. Oh man.
- Give her some space, everybody.
The Jewel of Morro Bay, California.
The Jewel of Morro Bay, California?
I remembered something so I--
(GASPS) I remembered something!
I actually remembered something!
Something important.
Something important?
What? What was it?
Uh... I'm not sure any more,
but I can still feel it. It's right there.
All right, thank you, Mr Ray.
Okay, come on. Try to remember better.
Don't be such a Dory, Dory.
Hmm. I don't know. I-- Hold on. Hold on.
- Uh... Oh. Oh!
- What? Did you remember?
Ugh, I don't remember.
It was something-- It was--
Oh, oh, oh! It was something about the--
- The Jewel of Morro Bay, California.
- (GASPS)
My family!
(GASPS) I remember my family!
They're out there somewhere.
I have to find them.
Guys, you got to help me.
Guys! Guys! Hello?
Guys! Where are you?
- MARLIN: Dory!
- Hello?
- Dory!
- Ah! Where did you go?
- You were the one to go.
- My parents. I remembered them.
What? What did you remember?
I remembered them! My mom. My dad.
I have a family. Oh! They don't know
where I am. Let's go. We have to go.
Dory, no. No! This is crazy!
Where exactly are you trying to go?
To the Gem of the Baltic?
- The Jewel of Morro Bay, California.
- Yes!
No, Dory. California's all the way
across the ocean.
Then we'd better get going.
How come every time we're on the edge
of this reef, one of us is trying...
to leave?
For once, can't we just enjoy the view?
How can you be talking about the view
when I remembered my family?
No! We've done our ocean travels.
That part of our lives is over.
The only reason to travel
in the first place is so...
- you don't have to travel ever again.
- Yeah, but I want to--
(MARLIN GROANS AND COUGHS)
- Dory, look--
- Please.
All I know is that I miss them.
I really, really miss them.
I didn't know what that felt like.
Do you know what that feels like?
(SIGHS)
Yes, I know what that feels like.
I don't want to forget this.
Somewhere out there is my family.
Please, Marlin,
I can't find them on my own.
I'll forget.
Please help me find my family.
Yeah, Dad, you can get us all the way
across the ocean. Right?
No. (SIGHS)
But I know a guy.
- Whoo-hoo!
- (MARLIN SCREAMING)
Righteous, righteous, righteous!
(LAUGHTER)
Totally sick. Totally sick.
I know. Isn't it great?
No! I'm gonna be totally sick.
It's the California current, dude.
It's got some gnarly chop.
- (GROANING)
- Surf's up, dude!
(MARLIN SCREAMS AND GAGS)
Hey, dude, if you're gonna hurl,
just do me a solid...
head to the back of the shell,
lean out, and go for distance.
We call that "feeding the fishes."
Correctamundo, Squirt!
And now we're looking for my parents
at the Brooch of the Atlantic? Or the--
- The Jewel of Morro Bay, California.
- Exactly!
How are you gonna find your parents?
Do you remember what they look like?
I'm a bit new to the memory thing,
so I can't say for sure...
but something tells me they were
mostly blue, with s-- Maybe yellow.
That sounds right.
Also I'm pretty sure I'm gonna know
them when I see them. We're family.
By the way crossing the ocean
is the kind of thing you should...
only do once. One time!
Morro Bay, California's
coming up, dudes.
DORY: Whoo-hoo!
Let's find my family.
CRUSH: Go! Go! Go, go, go.
NEMO: Just go, Dad.
MARLIN: Don't push me, Nemo.
(MARLIN SCREAMING)
- (MARLIN GROANS)
- (NEMO LAUGHING)
Whoo-hoo! (LAUGHS)
SQUIRT: So long, Little Blue!
Hope you find your parents.
CRUSH: And good luck
"feeding the fishes."
(TURTLES LAUGHING)
Too late. Already fed.
Oh.
This feels familiar. Mom! Dad!
MARLIN: No. Dory! Dory! Wait! Wait.
DORY: Mom! Dad!
MARLIN: Stop yelling for a second.
Do you really think your parents...
are just gonna be floating around here
waiting for you?
Well, I don't know, but there's only
one way to find out. Mom! Dad!
- Yell louder, Dory.
- Mom! Dad!
- Sh!
- (GASPS) What was that?
Wait. I've heard that before.
I remember someone saying, "Sh."
Yes, well done. That was me.
One minute ago.
ALL: Sh!
(GASPS)
Please. Have you seen
my mommy and daddy?
Their names are Jenny and Charlie.
ALL: Sh!
(GASPS) Jenny and Charlie.
MARLIN: What? Jenny and what?
Those are their names!
My parents are Jenny and Charlie!
- Dory, wait!
- Jenny!
MARLIN: Can't we just take
a moment to come up with a plan?
- Jenny! Charlie!
- Sh!
- Are you crazy?
- Sorry, she's a little excited.
- Jenny! Charlie!
- Dory, stop yelling for a second.
It's not a good idea
to come into a new neighbourhood...
and call this much attention to yourself.
You don't understand. I remembered
my parent's names! Jenny! Charlie!
These crabs are locals and I
get the feeling they're shushing...
us for a reason. You might wake up
something dangerous.
Are you talking about like
something with one big eye...
tentacles, and a snappy thing?
Well, that's very specific,
but something like that, yes.
You just in general don't want to--
(CRABS GASP)
Oh my goodness. Okay.
There's a mistake. We're backing away.
Let us live and we will--
We'll worship you. We'll build a--
Do you like a monument?
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
MARLIN: Oh! Ooh! Whoa!
Swim for your life!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(NEMO SCREAMS)
- Nemo!
Dad!
- Dad!
No!
Nemo, hold on to me and don't let go!
Dad!
No, no! No!
(MARLIN GRUNTS)
(DORY PANTING)
Dory! Dory, slow down!
We're not being chased any more.
Are you sure? (SCREAMS)
(DORY GRUNTS)
Jenny and Charlie. Jenny and Charlie!
I just remembered their names!
We have to keep going. We're so close.
- Huh?
- Nemo, are you hurt?
(GASPS) Oh my goodness! Nemo!
Are you okay? What happened?
- Not now, Dory. Please!
- Oh no.
- Nemo. Oh no. Oh no.
- I'm okay.
Oh, Nemo. I'm sorry. Okay. I'm sorry.
(GASPS)
Oh my goodness! Nemo, are you okay?
I said, "Not now." You've done enough.
I have? Oh no. But I can fix it.
I can. I'll go get help.
You know what you can do, Dory?
You can go wait over there.
Go wait over there and forget.
It's what you do best.
You're right. I don't know why I thought
I could do this.
Find my family. I can't do this.
I'm so sorry. I'll fix it.
- NEMO: I'm okay.
- Well, I'm gonna get help. Okay?
Okay? I can do that. I'll be--
It'll be all right, Nemo.
Hello? Someone? Hello?
Anyone? Hello? Anyone?
SIGOURNEY ON SPEAKER: Hello.
- Hello?
- I'm Sigourney Weaver.
Oh. Hi, Sigourney. I need your help.
Won't you please join us...
Oh. Great, great, great.
As we explore the wonders
of the Pacific Ocean...
and the amazing life it holds within.
Witness the majesty
of the Beluga Whale.
Sigourney Weaver, where are you?
Dory! There you are!
Guys! I found help. Sigourney Weaver's
gonna tell us where we are.
- Look out!
- (SCREAMS)
- Oh, look at this!
- No respect for ocean life.
- Marlin! Nemo!
- NEMO: Dory!
No, no, no. Not again! Not again!
Let's take her inside
and see how she does.
(DORY SCREAMS)
NEMO: Dory! Dory!
MARLIN: Don't worry, Dory! Stay calm.
We'll come find you!
SIGOURNEY: And welcome to
the Marine Life Institute...
where we believe in Rescue,
Rehabilitation and Release.
DORY: Marlin? Nemo?
(DORY PANTING)
Hello? Hello? Can you help me?
Me help you? (SNEEZES)
Ugh. (SCREAMS)
Oh. (GASPS)
Huh? What's happening? Help?
MAN: Looks like we're done here.
WOMAN: Dude, cut it out.
You're a scientist. We talked about this.
MAN: Oh, come on. It's funny.
(DOOR CLOSES)
DORY: Oh boy. Okay. This is--
I'll be fine, I just need to find
a way out and...
If I could just-- Get a hold of yourself,
- get a hold of yourself.
- (YELPS)
You'll be fine, everything's fine,
think positively.
- Hey, you.
- Oh.
Spinner.
Oh, thank goodness. Hi, I'm Dory. I'm--
Name's Hank. How sick are you?
Sick? I'm sick?
Why else would you be in quarantine?
Oh no! How long do I have?
I have to find my family.
All right. Now don't get hysterical--
Uh-oh. Not good.
What? What is it? What happened?
(GASPS) What's that?
That there is bad news.
It's a transport tag for fish
who can't cut it inside the institute.
They get transferred to permanent digs.
An aquarium.
In Cleveland.
Fish in here, go back in the ocean.
Cleveland fish, stay there forever.
(GASPS) Cleveland? No!
I can't go to the Cleveland.
I have to get to the Jewel of Morro Bay,
California and find my family.
That's this place.
The Marine Life Institute.
The Jewel of Morro Bay, California.
You're here.
You mean I'm from here?
(GASPS) My parents are here.
I have to get to them.
So what exhibit are you from?
Wait. I'm from an exhibit?
Which one? I have to get there.
Hmm. That's a hard one, kid.
Unless... Nah.
Never work. It's too crazy.
What do you mean? Just tell me.
I'm okay with crazy.
You know, I could see that?
Well, there's one thing I can think of...
to help you get to your family.
If I just take--
Yes! Great idea.
You take me to find them.
Why didn't I think of that?
Uh, no, no, no.
If I just take your tag...
I can take your place on the transport
truck then you can go back inside...
and find your family.
All you have to do is give me the tag.
What tag?
(GASPS) There's a tag on my fin!
How could you forget
you have a tag on your fin?
Oh no. I'm sorry. I--
I suffer from short-term memory loss.
You don't remember
what we were talking about?
Mm-mm. Not a clue.
What were we talking about?
Um, you were about to give me your tag.
Well, I kind of like my tag.
Why do you want it?
So I can go to--
So I can go to Cleveland.
Cleveland? Mmm.
I hear good things
about Cleveland.
Why do you want to go?
Because if I stay here I'm gonna get
released back to the ocean.
And I have extremely
unpleasant memories of that place.
(EXHALES)
I just want to live in a glass box alone.
That's all I want. So give me your tag!
Hey, man, don't touch my tag!
(SIGHS)
Look...
(SLURPS)
I don't work here.
It's not like I have a map of this place.
(GASPS) A map! Good idea.
You take me to the map, I figure out
where my parents are. Oh boy.
All right. If I get you to your family
will you give me--
I don't have much. Um, I--
How about if I give you this tag?
Great idea.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MARLIN: Are you absolutely
sure that's what I said?
"Go wait over there and forget.
That's what you do best."
- Yeah, Dad.
- I said that?
You said that, Dory swam to the surface,
and she got taken by some--
All right, I don't want to hear
the whole story again.
I was just asking about the one part
because, look, if I said that--
I'm not positive I did.
It's actually a compliment because...
I asked her to wait and I said,
"It's what you do best."
So I-- Oh, it's my fault!
It's all my fault she got kidnapped
and taken into whatever this place is.
What if it's a restaurant?
Oy! You two! Shut it!
Yeah, we're trying to sleep!
You interrupted my favourite dream!
Is that the one about you
laying on this rock?
- Yeah.
- Oh, that is a good one.
- Oh yeah, isn't it? Yeah.
- It's one of my favourites.
NEMO: Uh, excuse us. Hello!
- Son! Son.
- We're trying to--
Those are sea lions.
They are natural predators.
They could pounce at any moment.
(YAWNING)
Uh, they don't look very pouncy.
That's what they want you to think.
Just get behind me
and let me do the talking.
Excuse me, we're worried
about our friend. Is that a restaurant?
(LAUGHING)
Mate, it's not a restaurant.
Your friend is okay.
- She is?
- It's a fish hospital.
Sigourney Weaver says she'll be
rescued, rehabilitated, and released.
She'll be in and out in a jiff.
We should know.
- Nasal parasite.
- Anaemia.
All fixed up and sent on our way.
Oh thank goodness.
Sure, that's all right.
Don't you worry ab--
- BOTH: Gerald, get off the rock!
- Shove off, Gerald! Come on. Off! Off!
- Get off! Now you know better! Off!
- Off! Off! Off! Off!
Don't you worry about a thing.
That place is the Marine Life Institute.
The Jewel of Morro Bay, California.
(GASPS) She was right.
It looks like Dory
can do something besides forget.
Thank you, Nemo. Thank you for that.
So how are we gonna get inside?
Wait. You want to get inside MLI?
Desperately. Our friend is in there.
Lost, alone.
She's scared.
She'll have no idea what to do.
Oh, we know a way.
You do?
BOTH: Ooo-roo.
Ooo-roo-roo. Ooo-roo.
- What are they doing?
- I don't know. It sounds bad.
DORY: Are we there yet?
HANK: Sh. Keep it down!
Hank, I'm so glad I found you.
It feels like-- I-- Destiny.
For what must be the millionth time,
it's not destiny.
Uh-oh. Have I said "destiny" before?
I'm sorry.
I'm just so nervous
because I'm gonna meet my parents.
I haven't seen them in I don't even know
how long because...
- you see I suffer from short-term--
- HANK: Short-term memory loss.
Look, no more talking. Okay?
I don't like talking.
I don't like chatter and questions.
And, "How are you? Oh I'm fine."
(PHONE RINGING)
"How are you? I'm fine too."
News flash -nobody's fine.
Oh, I'm fine. How are you?
(SIGHS)
- Hank, look, there's a map!
- Sh!
The plan is you're gonna read that
and figure out where your parents live.
Then I'm on the truck to Cleveland.
You got it?
Got it. What was the first part again?
Ugh.
What? The octopus escaped again?
Wow. Look at all the exhibits.
How can you do this park in one day?
Seriously.
- Pick one!
- Okay. Um...
(GROANS) Well,
tell everyone to keep an eye out.
We're supposed to be releasing
the octopus back to the ocean today.
Well, of course I haven't seen him.
If I was looking I'd find him.
Hank! There you are.
- Hurry up!
- Okay. Okay.
K. It starts with a "k."
Kid z-own-y. Kid zone!
No! No kids. Kids grab things.
And I'm not losing
another tentacle for you.
You lost a tentacle?
Well then you're not an octopus,
you're a septopus.
I may not remember, but I can count.
- Hurry up!
- Okay.
Journey to the-- Hey, look. Shells.
(GASPS)
Hey, look. Shells!
(CHARLIE CHUCKLING)
Daddy, here's a shell for you.
That's great, Dory.
You found another one.
- I did?
- Oh, yes, you did.
You're getting good at this, Dory.
(FISH LAUGHING)
Hey, look. Shells!
(JENNY CHUCKLES)
- Hey, I live there.
- Yes! Yes, indeed.
- I like shells.
- (LAUGHS) That's right, dear.
Do you think you could find me
another shell?
(WHISPERS) Purple ones
are my favourite.
Okay, Mommy.
Mommy. Purple shell. Purple shell!
Hey, my home had a purple shell.
So what? Half the exhibits here
have purple shells in them.
No, no, no. You don't understand.
I remember her now.
Purple shells were her favourite
and she had this adorable giggle.
And then my dad was really friendly.
And now your wacky memory's
gonna get us caught.
Still think this is destiny?
- Hank, we have to find my folks!
- Quiet!
Ugh. Base, this is Carol.
Uh, I think I might have found
that missing octopus. Over.
- See what you did?
- Sorry.
This could not be worse.
Hmm. "Destiny." (GASPS) Destiny.
- Hank. I got a feeling.
- Sh!
I think we should get in the bucket.
- No. Stop.
- Seriously. It says "destiny" and it is--
- No, no, no, no, no.
- We've got to get in that bucket.
- I'm not going with you in that bucket.
- Here...I...go...in...the...bucket. Bye.
(GASPS)
Hey, guys, I'm looking for my family.
Oh, good idea. Play dead.
(HANK GASPS)
I'm sorry. I got to blink. How do you
hold your eyes open that long?
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Hey, guys. Wait a second.
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
Our next guest
has been here a very long time.
She's a whale shark.
Her name is Destiny.
Destiny? Really?
You'll notice she's extremely
near-sighted and has trouble...
navigating her environment.
Oh! And here she comes now.
Ooh! Destiny. (GASPS) You're a fish?
(DESTINY GROANS)
Wait. What?
- Hi! Hello there.
- Whoa! Oh. Whoa.
All right, I'll go with you.
- Excuse me.
- Is that blue blob talking?
- Can you help me? I lost my family.
- You lost your family?
Well, it's a long story,
and truth be told,
I don't remember most of it.
Aw, that is so sad.
You poor thi-- (SCREAMS)
(DESTINY PANTING)
Sorry. Not a great swimmer.
I can't see very well.
Oh, I think you swim beautifully.
In fact, I've never seen a fish
swim like that before.
(VOCALISING) Thank you.
(VOCALISING) You're welcome.
Wait. Say that again.
Um, you're (VOCALISING) welcome.
- Dory?
- Yes.
- (GASPS) Dory!
- You and I were friends!
- No!
- Dory, it's me! Destiny!
- You know me?
Of course! We talked through the pipes
when we were little.
- We were pipe pals!
- We were?
- (GASPS) Aw, you're so pretty.
- So you know where I'm from?
Yep, you are from
the Open Ocean exhibit.
I'm from the Open Ocean exhibit?
(GASPS) Then that's
where my parents are.
We got to go. Can you take me there?
Uh... Kind of tough for a whale
to travel around here.
Can you please keep it down
over there? My head hurts.
- (DESTINY GROANS)
- Who's that?
(WHISPERING)
That's my neighbour, Bailey.
He was brought in with a head injury.
I know you're talking about me, Destiny.
He thinks he can't use his echolocation,
but I've overheard...
the doctors talking.
There's not a thing wrong with him.
Hear every word
you're saying about me.
What's echolocation?
Bailey's head is supposed to put out
a call and the echo helps him...
find objects far away.
Oh, but apparently he's still "healing."
Now I know you're talking about me.
- I really can't echolocate.
- Oh.
I cannot have this conversation again.
I just can't.
I hit my head very hard out there.
See how swollen it is!
Your head is supposed to be big!
You're a beluga!
Echolocation.
Oh, like the world's
most powerful pair of glasses?
- What?
- What are glasses?
It's sort of like you go, "hoo"
and then you see things.
Why do I know that?
Oh. That's interesting.
There you are!
Listen up, you and I are square.
I took you to the map,
now give me that tag!
Wait, no. I know where my parents are.
They're in the--
What's it called? The place--
The soap and lotion?
- BOTH: Open Ocean.
- Open Ocean!
(GASPS) Open Ocean!
I know where that is.
That's the exhibit located right next to--
I don't care.
- Easy!
- (DESTINY GASPS)
If you're trying to get to the Open Ocean
exhibit go through the pipes.
- HANK: Through the pipes. Great.
- Through the pipes?
Yep. Take two lefts, swim straight
and you'll hit it.
Oh, that's a lot of directions. That's--
Did you get that, Hank? All that?
- Uh, yeah.
- Great! Let's go.
I'm not going with you. I won't fit.
You have to go by yourself.
Um...
That's-- I'm-- I-- See, I can't because
I'm not so good with directions.
Well, that's too bad. A deal's a deal.
You wanted to find your parents?
That's how you get to them.
Now give me your tag.
But, Hank, I can't go in the pipes alone.
I'll forget where I'm going.
- Not my problem. Tag!
- But I can't get in that way.
- I'm sorry, but there's no other way.
- There's no other way. (GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
- There's no other way.
- Now, now. Don't panic.
It's okay. Not everything in life is
easy to do. Isn't that right, Charlie?
She's right. When something's
too hard, you should just give up.
- Charlie!
- A joke. I'm kidding!
Just a joke. A joke.
Caution, joker at work.
- Joke. I got it.
- (BABY DORY LAUGHS)
You see, kelpcake?
There's always another way.
Thank you, Daddy.
(GASPS) Nope. My father said
there's always another way.
- What? There is no other way.
- Open Ocean. Open Ocean. Hmm...
Open Ocean. I'm pretty sure
it's the building over there.
That's ill-defined and roundish.
Like Bailey's head.
- Wait, what?
- Always another way. There's--
There! Guys, follow me.
I know how we can get to locomotion.
BOTH: Open Ocean.
DORY: Exactly.
Um, guys.
You know I can't swim over there, right?
BOTH: Ooo-roo, ooo-roo, ooo-roo.
MARLIN: I don't see how this
is going to get us inside.
What are you even doing?
We're calling her over, of course.
Calling her over? Calling who over?
(BIRDS WARBLING)
Lads, meet Becky.
(SQUAWKS)
Flying? No, no, no new information.
Listen, tell her thank you.
You guys have gone
above and beyond. Really.
But is there a way to get in
that involves, like, swimming?
Because that's really our strength.
Look, your friend is going to be
in quarantine.
That's where they take the sick fish.
And the one and only one way
into that place is Becky.
- (SQUAWKS)
- (MARLIN SCREAMS)
(MARLIN CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Hi, Becky.
Ow! Stop. Let's call
her Pecky because this is hurting.
(CHUCKLES) I think she likes you, Dad.
Becky, love? These two nice fish
need to get into quarantine.
Are you free today, Rebecca darling?
Becky, is-- Would that work
with your schedule? Ow!
She doesn't understand
what I'm saying.
All you have to do
is imprint with her, mate.
- Imp-- What?
- BOTH: Imprint.
Look her in the eye and say, "ooo-roo"
and she'll be in sync with you.
- Now look her in the eye.
- Yeah.
(GROANS) Nemo, I think we should
devise an alternate plan.
One that involves staying in the water
and someone sane.
Because this bird, this bird...
This ain't the bird!
That's fine, Dad. And in the meantime,
Dory will just forget us.
Like you said, it's what she does best.
(SIGHS) Fine.
Uh...
Okay, look her in the eye. Which eye?
FLUKE: Just pick one, mate.
MARLIN: Becky.
Uh...
(ECHOING) Ooh. Ooo-roo.
Roo-roo, Becky.
(SQUAWKS)
(NEMO LAUGHING)
Okay, this is all great.
How exactly is Becky
supposed to carry us?
Oh yeah. I almost forgot. Gerald!
- Hmm?
- RUDDER: Yeah, Gerald.
- FLUKE: Come on, son.
- Hmm?
Come on, Gerald. Give us your pail,
we'll let you sit on the rock.
- Yeah, Gerald. We swear it.
- Hmm.
(LAUGHS)
That's right. Shimmy on over here.
- (LAUGHING)
- Come on. You can do it.
- That's right.
- (GRUNTING)
Mind you don't scuff your bum.
(GRUNTING)
- Thank you so much, Gerald.
- (LAUGHING)
Welcome to your time on this rock.
- Comfortable, isn't it?
- (CHUCKLES)
BOTH: Time's up! Get off!
- Off! Off! Off! Off!
- Time's up! Now get off, Gerald! Off!
No, this is nuts! Why do I keep getting
talked into insane choices?
- (BECKY SQUAWKS)
- Good luck!
(SCREAMING)
Okay, when I tell you you're gonna--
Yeah. I know. I'm gonna signal
with a big splash.
On my mark. Not clear yet.
Not clear yet.
- Now?
- Not 'til Destiny gives the signal.
(HANK CHEWING LOUDLY)
You know something? I have no idea
why you're even doing this.
What do you mean?
It seems like a lot of trouble
just to find some more fish.
If I had short-term memory loss...
I'd just swim off into the blue
and forget everything.
Well I don't want to do that.
I want my family.
Not me, kid. I don't want anyone
to worry about.
You're lucky. No memories.
No problems.
Huh. No memories. No problems.
Still not clear. Still not clear.
You don't have to say when it's not time.
- Not--
- Just tell me when it is time.
Okay, here we go. And-- Wait!
(INHALES) "Here we go. Wait."
Are you serious?
- Okay, on the count of three.
- Don't count. Just say, "Go."
- Go! Now, now. Do it! Do it!
- What? Okay, okay. (GRUNTS)
- Wow. Look at that! I mean--
- That's the signal.
- Go, go, go! That's the signal!
- (GRUNTING)
HANK: Now remember,
Destiny said follow the signs
- to the Open Ocean exhibit.
- DORY: Uh-huh.
HANK: I can't see squat,
so it's your job to look for it.
Got it. Follow the signs to Open Ocean.
I'm just gonna repeat it, okay?
That should work.
Follow the signs to Open Ocean.
Mm. Go right! Follow the signs
to Open Ocean.
Follow the signs to Open Ocean.
Follow the signs to Open Ocean. Left!
- Follow the signs to Open Ocean.
- And steer clear of people, will you?
Especially kids.
I don't want to be touched.
Sh! Do not mess me up!
(BOTH SCREAM)
Oh, poor baby.
Let me get that for you. Here you-- Oh!
Oh my. Ugh.
- Where do we go? Where do we go?
- (GIRL CRYING)
Oh, sorry!
Okay, I was looking, looking...
MARLIN: Roo-roo, Becky!
Drop us anywhere. We're okay.
Just wait, Dad. I think she's looking
for a place to land.
She's confused, Nemo. She doesn't
even know which way to look.
(GIRL CRYING)
(SQUAWKS)
(MARLIN SCREAMING)
Wait, Becky. What are you doing?
Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo-roo-roo-roo.
(SQUAWKS)
Okay. I was going somewhere.
The question is where.
Which way? Do you see the sign?
I'm looking. I'm looking. Something to
something gets me to my family!
"The world's most powerful pair of--"
I know that. Why do I know that?
It's another memory.
Hank, we need to go that way!
Left. Go left.
MARLIN: Becky! Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo.
She can't hear you, Dad.
All right. New plan. We have to get
closer to Becky so she can hear us.
- (GRUNTING)
- I don't think we should move the pail.
Nemo. Without me Becky's lost.
Dad, just trust her.
Trust her? So she can forget us
all together?
- I trust Becky.
- You trust her? Becky's eating a cup!
(SQUAWKS)
Becky! Becky! Ooo-roo! Whoa!
Ah. (GROANS)
Well, at least we're not stuck
in the bucket any more.
- (MARLIN GROANS)
- (NEMO SIGHS)
Or on top of quarantine.
SIGOURNEY: The baby otter talk
is beginning now.
Why, thanks, Sigourney Weaver.
Hey, who wants to learn about otters?
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
DORY: Looking for the world's
most powerful pair of glasses.
(GASPS) Otters!
- Welcome, it's a huge cuddle party!
- Cuddle party! I'm in!
Where are we?
Are we close to Open Ocean?
Uh, yes. I think-- Well, I don't know.
But I saw that other sign so--
What? What other sign?
The world's most powerful
pair of glasses.
What? What are you talking about?
Why would we follow that sign?
Well, because I remembered it.
No. That wasn't the plan. Ow!
All right, that's it!
You have wasted my time!
- Wait. No.
- That transport truck leaves at dawn...
and I'm not missing it,
so give me your tag.
Wait. No, I remembered that sign.
- So?
- So I'm remembering more...
and more and I feel like my memory's
getting better. I think we should--
No! Your memory is not working.
You can't remember anything.
It's probably how you lost your family
in the first place!
(GASPS)
All right, look, let's just take it down
a notch. Just give me the tag and--
You know something, for a guy
with three hearts you're not very nice.
Three hearts? What are you talking
about? I don't have three hearts.
- Yes, you do.
- I don't!
- You do!
- Don't!
- Do!
- Stop saying that!
Fun fact- the octopus has three hearts.
Two pump blood to the gills
while the third pumps...
- blood throughout the body.
- Wait!
Whoa! (SCREAMING)
You know, someone with three hearts
shouldn't be so mean.
And it's mean to say that
I would lose someone I love!
I did not lose them! Hank?
Hank? Hank?
- Han-s.
- No. Not Hans. I'm looking for Hank.
- Hank. With a "k." Hank.
- Hands!
- Hands? Oh, oh, oh, hands!
(SCREAMS)
- Hank! Hank?
- (GROANING)
My arm!
Hank!
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
(SCREAMS) Where are you? Hank!
Oh! Ahh! Can you please help me?
I'm looking for--
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Please help me. I've lost
my friend Frank. I'm sorry, not Frank.
You're in my space! (SCREAMS)
He's an octopus. No, septo--
Septopus. That's right.
He's a septopus. Septopus.
Septopus. Septopus. (GASPS)
One, two, three, four, five, six, s--
Septopus! He's camouflaged!
(PANTING)
(YELPS)
Hank. Come on, Hank!
Let's get out of here.
- (GRUNTING)
- Dory, what are you doing?
(STAMMERING) Hank!
What's the plan?
The plan is I'm gonna stay here forever.
Okay. Good plan.
(SCREAMING)
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Hank. I'm sorry.
I can't remember right. (GASPS)
- Sweetie. Sweetie.
- Oh, watch out, kelpcake.
Oh, watch where you're going.
I'm sorry, Daddy.
I'm sorry I can't remember right.
Oh, sweetie.
Sweetie, you don't need to be sorry.
You know what you need to do?
Just keep swimming.
Yeah.
And I bet you can remember
that because we're just--
Um...
We're gonna sing a song about it.
♪ Just keep swimming
Just keep swimming
BOTH: ♪ Just keep swimming
Swimming, swimming
♪ What do we do?
We swim
♪ Swim, swim, swim
- ♪ We swim, swim, swim
- DORY: ♪ Just keep swimming ♪
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS) My parents
taught me that song!
We sang it as a family.
All this time I thought I made it up!
- What song?
- Just keep swimming.
Hank, we've just got to keep swimming.
What? No way! Listen to me,
it's too dangerous to move.
No, you listen to me. I know
you're scared, but you can't give up.
Follow me.
♪ Just keep swimming
Just keep swimming
(SCREAMS)
♪ My mom wrote
this song for me
(BOTH SCREAM)
♪ It's gonna get us out of here ♪
Sing with me, Hank. Come on.
(GASPS) I'm coming, Mommy.
I'm coming, Daddy!
- We're gonna be okay.
- Stop!
- Huh?
- Turn back.
Turn back!
ALL: You're headed
right for Poker's Cove.
Poker's Cove.
- Poker's Cove?
- Incoming!
(GRUNTING)
- (SCREAMS)
- Stop it!
CHILDREN: Oh, what is this?
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
HANK: Sorry.
DORY: That's okay. Everybody does it.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
Hank? Oh, Hank. There you are.
Wow. You got us out of there.
Huh. I did.
I got us out of there.
I mean, technically
you also got us in there.
But if you hadn't I'm not sure
we would have gotten here.
Echolocation. Echolocation!
The world's most powerful pair
of glasses. We found it!
No. You found that.
(GASPS)
SIGOURNEY ON SPEAKERS:
Welcome to the Open Ocean.
Home.
MARLIN: Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo, ooo-roo.
Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo.
Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo, ooo-roo!
Dad, stop. She's not coming back.
She might. Ooo-roo, ooo-roo!
Dad! You made her feel like
she couldn't do it.
You're not talking about Becky, are you?
(SIGHS)
I miss Dory.
Me too.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
The truth is,
I'm just so worried about her.
She's the one who should be worried
about us.
Well, she would definitely have an idea
of what to do if she were here.
I don't know how she does that.
I don't think she knows, Dad.
She just does.
Well, then we'll just have to think.
- What would Dory do?
Yeah! What would Dory do?
She would assess her situation,
and then she'd evaluate...
then she would analyse her options--
Dad, that's "what would Marlin do."
Right, that's what I would do.
She wouldn't even think twice.
She would just look at the first thing
she sees and--
- (GASPS)
- (CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
Dory would do it.
Mmm.
- Nemo, hold on to me.
- (BOTH INHALE SHARPLY)
Whoa!
(MARLIN SCREAMING)
NEMO: Whoo-hoo!
Hey, it's working! Whoa!
(BOTH GASPING)
Just keep gasping.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
- Are you okay?
- Yeah! What would Dory do now?
Who's Dory?
Oh boy. Are we happy to see you.
Happy to see me? I'm happy to see you!
I haven't had anyone to talk to in years.
Years? Wow.
Unfortunately we can't stay long.
We have to go because--
Now why would you want to go?
You just landed.
Stay a while. Tell me all about yourself.
I would love to, but my son and I
have to get to quarantine, so--
- Wonderful thing to have a son.
- Yeah it is.
Of course I don't have a family.
I dated a nice scallop for a while.
- That's fascinating, but--
- But scallops have eyes.
And she was looking for something
different. I'm kidding!
Well, not about scallops having eyes.
They do.
And they see into your soul
and they break your heart.
Oh, Shelley! Why? Why?
Now what would Dory do?
SIGOURNEY ON SPEAKERS:
Come with us as we explore
the mysterious world
of the Open Ocean.
- Okay, Hank, follow me.
- You're in a cup.
Right. I'll follow you then.
(HANK GRUNTS)
(GRUNTS)
- Wait.
- An octopus has three hearts.
- Huh. That's a fun fact.
- (GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(WHISTLING)
DORY: We're here.
This is really happening.
HANK: Sh!
Well, looks like this is it, kid.
Now I got a truck to catch.
Wait! Wait! I had something for you.
(HANK CHUCKLES)
- Tag.
- The tag. Right!
You know,
I think I'm gonna remember you.
Oh, you'll forget me in a heartbeat, kid.
Three heartbeats.
I'll have a hard time
forgetting you though.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
My parents are actually down there.
Um...
You okay?
I'm ready.
(CHUCKLING) Yeah, I think you are.
Whoa!
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Wow!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Where are they? Where are they?
Where are they? Okay. Okay.
Pardon me. Oh. Hi. Hello. Have you
seen a mom and a dad without me?
Excuse me. Have you seen a couple?
- They're old like you.
- (GASPS)
Not old like you,
but older than you even.
Okay. Bye.
Hi. Do you know anyone who lost a kid
a long time ago that would be me?
I don't know how long ago exact--
Okay. You're in a hurry. (GRUNTS)
- Ho, ho! Watch where you're going.
- Oh sorry.
(GASPS)
SIGOURNEY: It's our goal that every
animal we rescue and care for...
will eventually return home
to where they belong.
Shells.
And there we go.
Now, if you ever get lost, Dory...
You just follow the shells.
Hey, look! Shells!
(GASPS)
(BABY DORY LAUGHING)
Follow the shells.
- Hey, I live there.
- Yes, yes indeed.
(GASPS) My home. That's my home!
Mom! Dad!
Okay, kelpcake. Now count to ten.
One, two, three...
- (GASPS)
- BABY DORY: Four...
(VOCALISING) You're welcome.
Who are you talking to, kelpcake?
My pipe pal, Destiny!
Mom? Dad?
Mommy loves purple shells.
(GASPS)
(SINGING)
(JENNY CRYING)
- Mommy?
- What's going to happen to her?
There, there, Jenny.
Oh no, don't cry, Mommy. Don't cry.
Do you think she's-- That she can
make it on her own, Charlie?
Oh, honey. It'll be okay.
Mommy loves purple shells.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
- Dory!
- Dory?
- Mommy?
(SCREAMS)
- CHARLIE: Dory!
- Mommy! Daddy!
(GASPING)
My parents...
I... I lost them.
It was my fault.
- FEMALE CRAB: Where's your tag?
- Huh?
Your tag. It's missing.
That why you're not in quarantine?
- Quarantine?
- Yeah!
That's where they took all
the blue tangs. Isn't that right, Bill?
Yep. The blue tangs are getting
their own exhibit in Cleveland.
Being shipped out on a truck
at the crack of dawn. Must be nice.
What? No! No, my parents
are back in quarantine?
They're being shipped to Cleveland?
But I just got here!
I've got to get to them.
They don't know I'm here.
Don't worry,
it's easy to get to quarantine.
You can just go through the pipes,
honey.
Oh. Oh I can't do that.
- Why not?
- I'll forget where I'm going.
And I can't be somewhere
where I have nobody to help me.
- Well, then I guess you're stuck here.
- You're not helping, Bill.
Just go in there if you want to.
You'll be fine.
Oh boy.
Could you tell me how to get there?
Through the pipes?
Sure, honey. It's two lefts
and then a right. Simple.
Okay.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Two lefts and a right. I can do this.
Two lefts and a right. Okay.
Don't forget.
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
Two lefts and a right.
Two lefts and a right. Two lefts
and a right. Two lefts and a right.
Two lefts and a right? Shoot.
Left and a right. Wait.
Did I already take a left?
Oh no. It's happening. Okay, hold on.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Which way? Where am I going?
I can't remember. Okay.
Okay. I'm lost. It's too hard.
I can't remember.
I'm forgetting everything.
I'm gonna be stuck forever in the pipes.
The pipes! The pipe pals.
Pipe pals? Pipe pals!
- And...swim, swim, swim.
- Yeah, I don't know about this.
Trust me,
I won't let you hit anything. Wall!
(DESTINY GROANS)
What's the point?
I'll never learn to get around!
You better! If you can't do it in here
you'll never do it out in the ocean.
Now really focus, okay? Wall!
- DORY: Destiny!
- (GASPS)
Dory? (VOCALISING) Hello?
(VOCALISING) I'm lost in the pipes
and my parents are in quarantine!
Hang on, Dory! Bailey!
You've got to use your echolocation!
You know it's broken!
Just stop it, and try the "Ooh" thing
Dory talked about, will you?
- But I don't think I can--
- Don't bail on me, Bailey!
Ooh!
Ooh! Ooh!
Come on, Bailey. What did you
just tell me, huh? Really focus!
Ooh! I feel stupid.
- Bailey.
- Sorry. Ooh!
- DORY: Hello?
- Here!
(VOCALISING) We're here!
- Guys-- Ooh! Guys-- Ooh!
- What? What is it?
I'm getting something! Ooh!
Here we go! Ooh! Oh yes! Ooh!
I can see the quarantine!
(LAUGHS) This is amazing!
Ooh! I can see everything!
And I can see you!
(VOCALISING) He can see you!
My life's a rainbow! Can you see me?
(LAUGHS) Right,
it doesn't work that way.
- Bailey!
- Okay! Tell Dory to go left!
(VOCALISING) He says go left!
(VOCALISING) Left?
(PANTING)
- Ooh! Straight!
- Straight!
- Ooh! Go right!
- Right!
Ooh! I'm light-headed! Ooh! Wait. Ooh!
I'm picking up something else.
Hold on! Let me zoom out.
BAILEY: Zzz... (GASPS)
Holy Neptune, she's not alone! Ooh!
- What is it?
- I can't tell! But it's coming for her.
Oh no! (VOCALISING) Dory, swim!
Swim the other way!
- What? Where?
- Go right!
- Right!
(GASPING)
No, my right!
Oh no! She's heading right towards it!
No! Dory, turn around!
That's great, Dory!
You're headed right toward us!
What? You want me to go right?
No! No! Not right. Oh, I can't look!
(PANTING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
- BOTH: Dory!
- Marlin?
- I knew it! You're okay!
- Oh my gosh!
BAILEY: It's consuming her!
It's eating her alive!
(BOTH CRYING)
- You're okay!
- You found me! How did you find me?
There was a crazy clam.
He wouldn't stop talking.
We just slowly backed away from him
and into these pipes.
And then we just started looking.
DESTINY: Dory! I'm sorry!
Okay, what was that?
Hang on. I got to take this.
It's okay! Sorry for what?
What? You're okay?
- Yes!
- DORY: I found Marlin and Nemo!
(LAUGHS)
Dad! Did you hear that?
Dory really does speak whale.
I heard.
It's bringing back some very bad
memories so let's get out of here.
I say we go this way.
Follow me. It's time to head home!
Wait, wait, wait! Um...
My parents are here.
- They are?
- You found your parents?
Well, not exactly. No. I mean not yet,
but, um, I know where they are.
I don't know exactly how to get there,
but I know that-- I'm getting help--
- DESTINY: Down to quarantine.
- Quarantine.
That's it! Oh, and I met
this septopus, super cranky...
but secretly kind of sweet, and he
got me into the exhibit... The exhibit.
Dory?
Do you think my parents
will want to see me?
What? Why wouldn't they
want to see you?
Because... I lost them?
Dory, your parents are going to be
overjoyed to see you.
They're going to have missed...
everything about you.
- Really?
- Do you know how we found you?
- Something about a clam? Or...
- No.
- No, an oyster.
- Mollusc?
- No.
- Something?
- I don't... No?
- No clam.
We were having a very hard time
until Nemo thought...
"What would Dory do?"
Why would you say that?
Because ever since I've met you,
you've shown me how to do...
stuff I never dreamed of doing.
Crazy things!
Outsmarting sharks
and jumping jellyfish.
And finding my son.
You made all that happen.
Really? I didn't know you thought that.
Unless I forgot.
No, you didn't forget. I never told you.
And I'm sorry about that.
But, Dory, because of who you are,
you are about to find your parents.
And when you do that, you'll be home.
Dad.
Does this mean
we have to say goodbye to Dory?
Yes, Nemo. We do.
(DORY HUMMING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN 1: Hey, so how much more
we got left to load?
WOMAN: Uh, just this last row.
MAN 2: The sooner we finish,
the sooner this truck gets to Cleveland.
DORY: Watch the turn.
MARLIN: Watch what? Ow!
NEMO: Too late.
DORY: Okay, I think we're close. Whee!
(NEMO AND MARLIN SCREAMING)
ALL: Hi!
Is this quarantine?
DORY: Yes! This is it!
We're in quarantine!
- My parents are here!
- (ALL CHEERING)
MARLIN: Where are we going?
Hey, what--
No, why are we going towards the door?
- We are all better!
- ALL: Yay!
I feel fantastic!
- (SNEEZES)
- (ALL GASP)
Dude.
(GASPS)
My family! Come on, let's go!
Excuse me.
Dory, wait a minute!
I'm coming Mommy! I'm coming Daddy!
Whoo-hoo! Almost home.
Almost home. I'm almost home.
MARLIN: I think I'm getting
the hang of this! Oh!
(WHISPERING) I hear footsteps.
(ALL SCREAM)
- (GASPS) Hank!
- Quiet.
Hank, we need to get in that tank.
That rhymed.
- Why?
- Her parents are there!
Oh.
Look, you've got three minutes
to get everyone in this cup with you...
and then I'm on that truck
to Cleveland, got it?
Got it.
Oh boy.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Mom? Dad?
Hey, everybody. It's me, Dory!
(ALL GASP)
Dory? Dory? Dory?
Jenny and Charlie's Dory? Dory?
Mom? Dad?
- She should just pick 2 and let's go.
- Dad.
What? I'm kidding. It's a reunion.
Mom? Dad? Where are my parents?
Dory? Are you really
Jenny and Charlie's girl?
Yes, I am! That's me! Where are they?
Uh, well, Dory, right after
you disappeared, they thought you...
Well, they thought you must have
ended up here, in quarantine.
- Uh-huh?
- Come on, come on, come on.
And so they came here to look for you.
They're here! (GASPS) Where are they?
Dory, that was years ago.
- Huh?
- They never came back.
Oh no.
You see, Dory, when fish
don't come back from quarantine...
it means they're not...
What?
Dory, they're gone.
(GASPS) They're dead?
- (ECHOING) They wanted to find you...
- Wait. Are you sure they're gone?
Dory, listen, it's going to be okay.
Dory, they loved you so much.
Anyone not looking to go to Cleveland,
final warning!
(DORY BREATHING HEAVILY)
- NEMO: Dory, are you all right?
- Are you okay?
- I was too late.
- MARLIN: Dory, no. No. Now listen.
- I don't have a family.
- NEMO: No, Dory. That's not true.
HANK: Time to go!
I'm all alone.
MARLIN: Dory.
NEMO: Dory!
HANK: Where's everybody else?
Your orange friends are on their way
to Cleveland. Ah!
WOMAN: I found the octopus!
(SCREAMS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
- WOMAN: Where did he go?
- (DORY PANTING)
(DORY GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Mommy? Daddy?
Help.
No. No. No. Help. Help. Help me.
Help. Help me. Please.
Somebody help me!
Hey, can-- Help me?
Can you help me? I've lost them!
- Oh. Lost who?
- I-I-I-I...
Ah, sorry, honey. I can't help you
if you don't remember.
Uh... (GASPS)
Oh! Can you help me? I've lost...them.
Uh, can you be more specific?
My-- My-- Them! Them! Them!
Um... Um...
(PANTING)
Oh...
Help! Help!
Please? They're gone!
(CRYING)
I've lost... I've lost everyone.
(SNIFFLES) There's nothing I can do.
Shoot, I can't forget.
What was I forgetting? Something.
Something important. What was it? I--
What was it? It's going away.
It's going away. It's going because
all I can do is forget. I just forget.
And I forget.
That's what I do best. That's what I do.
What do I do? What do I do?
(GASPS)
What would Dory do?
I would look around.
And, um, there's just water over there.
And a lot of kelp over here.
Kelp is better. Okay.
(PANTING)
Okay. Now what? Lots of kelp.
It looks the same.
It all looks the same,
except there's a rock... over there.
And some sand this way.
I like sand. Sand is squishy.
(PANTING)
Oh this isn't going anywhere.
There's nothing here.
Nothing but kelp. Lots of kelp.
And some shells...this way.
I like shells.
I like...shells.
Whoa.
Hello. I'm--
- Dory!
- Dory! You're here.
- Oh my baby!
- You're really here.
- Let me look at you.
- You found us.
- I'm never letting you go again.
- Oh my missing girl, you're here.
- My baby!
- It's you.
- Yes! Oh absolutely!
- It's really you! Mom, you're here.
- I am, I...
- And Dad, so are you.
Right here, kelpcake.
(CRYING) I'm so sorry.
Oh honey. Oh honey, no. Kelpcake.
I know I've got a problem. I know I'm--
And I'm so sorry.
And all this time I've wanted to fix it
and I can't and I try. I try.
But my thoughts-- they leave my head
and ideas change.
And I'd forgotten you and I'm so sorry.
Dory. Don't you dare be sorry.
Look what you did.
- (SNIFFLES) What?
- You found us!
That's right. You found us.
Honey, why do you think
we stayed put here all these years?
Because we believed one day
you'd find us again.
Exactly!
But I thought you were gone.
How did you--
We went into quarantine
to look for you, but you weren't there.
And we knew you must have
gotten out through the pipes.
Through the pipes. That's right, sweetie.
And so we did too.
And we've stayed in this spot for you
ever since.
- We thought you might come back.
- We stayed and waited for you.
So every day, we go out and lay out...
Shells.
And you found us.
Oh honey, you found us.
And you know why you found us?
Because you remembered.
You remembered
in your own, amazing, Dory way.
(SNIFFLES)
I did. All by myself.
Oh, honey. Really? Have you been
by yourself all these years?
Oh, my poor little girl.
Oh, I haven't been all by myself--
(GASPS) Marlin and Nemo!
- Nobody saw where Dory went?
- ALL: No. Sorry. I didn't see anything.
Seriously? That's a lot
of eyeballs doing nothing.
Oh! Oh, excuse me. Can you help us?
- We're looking--
- Me help you?
(SNEEZES)
NEMO: (GASPS) Dad, look! It's Dory.
Oh, thank goodness. See, Nemo,
I knew she'd find a way-- What?
Hey, where's Dory? Is she with you?
(GASPS) I'm sorry.
I tried to hold on,
but I couldn't and I lost her.
- What?
- WOMAN: All right. Let's get going.
No!
DORY: And then the whale swallowed us
even though I speak whale.
JENNY: A whale?
CHARLIE: Good thing I wasn't
there to see that.
DORY: Actually Marlin never believes
I even know how to speak whale...
but you know what, he always kind of
trusts me anyway.
You know, I like this Marlin already.
Yeah. And then somehow
we found Nemo. Or did he find me?
I don't know. But, you know what,
Nemo is the sweetest.
He just never gives up on me
no matter what.
Um, what would Dory do?
Well, we'll certainly have to thank
Marlin and Nemo when we meet them.
(GRUNTS)
Wait. Wait I know this place.
SIGOURNEY ON SPEAKER:
Hello. I'm Sigourney Weaver.
- There!
- Won't you please join us?
- That's the Marine Life Institute.
- Oh, you were born there.
Dory, is that where your friends are?
Yes! They were stuck in something.
It was going somewhere.
(TRUCK ENGINE STARTS)
(GASPS) A truck. They're in the truck!
That means I could--
Never see them again!
No! No, no, no. What would Dory do?
Uh, I know they're good friends of yours,
but a truck is kind of a tall order.
Please! Please.
All I know is that I miss them. I-- I...
I really miss them.
I've said that before.
Um...
Dory?
Mom, Marlin and Nemo are more
than good friends, they're family.
And I have to get them back.
See, when they found me it felt like fate.
Do you know what I mean? Or... I don't--
What's another word for fate?
Like destiny. (GASPS) Destiny?
(VOCALISING) Destiny!
- Dory?
- Destiny!
- Morning, Dest--
- Sh. It's Dory. Something's wrong.
(GASPS) Ooh. I got her.
She's right outside the institute.
(DESTINY GROANS)
- DORY: Destiny?
- We got to jump.
- Jump?
- No time to argue!
Destiny!
Dory! The truck thing
with your friends is leaving!
No, no. (VOCALISING) Destiny.
JENNY: Oh no! That's bad!
What do we do?
- All right.
- Yes.
- Here we go. One. Two.
- Yes. Yes.
I can't! I can't do it!
I'll never make it out there.
Destiny! I've got the world's
most powerful pair of glasses.
You've got the world's
I will be your eyes.
You can be my eyes. But the walls!
There are no walls in the ocean!
- No walls?
- (WHISPERS) It's your destiny, Destiny.
Well, why didn't you say so?
What? No! Destiny, wait!
No, that's a wall! Wall!
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SCREAM)
Mom, Dad, this is my pipe pal.
Destiny, say hi.
Dory! Are these little blue blobs
your parents?
They look just like you!
Hello. I'm Bailey. Mrs Dory, Mr Dory.
- Oh please, call me Jenny.
- Oh and I'm Charlie.
Okay. Okay. We got to go.
We got to stop that truck.
Okay, what truck?
(DORY GASPS)
Bailey, status report.
Oh, yes, my beautiful gift. Ooh.
Found it! The truck's merging
onto the freeway
and it's heading south. Ooh.
Let's go. We are stopping that truck.
- This I've got to see.
- Yeah, yeah, me too!
- Oh boy, this is gonna be good!
- (GERALD SNICKERS)
What the-- Gerald!
Have you lost your marbles?
- Don't get used to it, Gerald!
- Cheeky joke.
(SNICKERING)
Bailey, I forgot everything.
Catch me up.
Yes, ma'am. Ooh.
Your friends are still on the truck.
Ooh. They're headed north
towards the bridge. Ooh.
Oh, look, there's a bunch of
cute otters over there.
I want one! Ow!
(SCREAMS)
Ow, Bailey!
Oh! I see the truck. It's over there.
- Okay, what would Dory do?
- I don't see how we can get on it.
Oh, man, if only there was a way
to stop traffic.
Stop traffic. Stop traffic!
Everyone needs to stop.
People stop to look at things.
Things that they like.
Things that are cute.
(GASPS) Things that are cute!
Okay, I got it.
- What? What is it?
- Quickly before I forget.
Destiny, when the truck reaches
the bridge you flip me up there.
Got it.
You guys, follow me.
Everyone else, stay here.
Whoa. Dory.
Honey, you're not leaving us again.
Your mother's right.
You have to stay with us.
Dory, what happens if--
You know, if you're gone for too long.
And what if you get confused and that
makes you distracted. And what if--
I lose you again?
Oh. Yes.
Mom, Dad,
it's gonna be okay because...
I know that even if I forget
I can find you again.
Ooh. Okay a little left. Ooh.
Back the other way a bit.
Ooh. Okay, that's it. Go! Don't do it.
- Bailey!
- Okay, now! Now! Do it! Do it!
- Time for your idea.
- Okay. What idea? (SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
Okay. What do I do?
What would Dory do?
Come on, cars, cars. I see cars.
Otters in front of cars.
Cars have to stop.
Stop traffic! Cuddle party!
(OTTERS CHITTERING)
Look out!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
They're so cute!
Look at them! There must be one, two...
(ALL GROANING)
- What's going on, Dad?
- I don't know how.
I don't know in what way, but I think
this has something to do with--
(PANTING)
- ALL: Dory!
- Water. Water. I need water.
Are you crazy? How'd you get here?
(GASPS)
- BOTH: Dory!
- Oh!
- I thought we'd never see you again.
- Aw, me too.
But, darn it, no matter how hard I tried
I just couldn't forget you.
I guess I missed the rest of my family
too much, huh?
- We're family?
- Mm-hmm.
Do you know what that feels like?
(SIGHS) Yes, I know what that feels like.
ALL: Aw!
Hey! Hey, come on. Out of the truck.
Those aren't your fish. Shoo!
- Oh no. There goes our ride.
- Back in the water. Come on.
(VOCALISING) Dory,
the traffic is starting to move.
Leave it to me. I got this.
(CLEARS THROAT) Ooo-roo. Ooo-roo.
Becky! Becky, come back.
We need your help! Becky!
- (BECKY SQUAWKING)
- (GASPS)
Dory, follow me.
No, no, wait. We don't have Dory!
No, no, Becky wait! Stop it.
We need to go back. Becky, back!
Back, Becky! Loo-loo. Ooo-roo-roo.
- (SCREAMS) Please don't eat us!
- Where's Dory?
- Who are you?
- Jenny?
- Marlin?
- Charlie?
- Nemo? Thank you so much.
- (SQUAWKS)
Thank you for taking care of Dory.
Dory! She's still in the truck.
Becky! Fetch Dory! Ooo-roo. Dor-roo.
(BECKY SQUAWKING)
Okay, kid. I guess this is goodbye.
- No!
- What do you mean, "No"?
You're not going to the Cleveland.
You are coming to the ocean with me.
What is it with you
and ruining my plans?
Listen to me, I have one goal in life.
One! And it is to--
No, you listen to me. What is so great
about plans? I never had a plan.
Did I plan to lose my parents? No.
Did I plan to find Marlin? No.
Did you and I plan to meet?
Wait. Did we?
- Are you almost done?
- Well, I don't think we did.
And that's because the best things
happen by chance. Because that's life.
That's you being with me out
in the ocean not safe in some glass box.
- Can I say something?
- I'm not done!
A friend of mine-- Her name's
Sigourney-- Once told me that...
all it takes is three simple steps:
Rescue, rehabilitation,
and one other thing--
ALL: Release! (CHEERING)
That's right! So what do you say?
ALL: (CHANTING)
Release! Release! Release!
- Release! Release! Release!
- (SQUAWKING)
I was gonna say, "Okay."
Not good.
JENNY: Oh no! They're going away!
NEMO: Oh no! Dory! What do we do?
Quick! Guys, grab my fin!
Ooh! He's trying to get the door open.
Ooh. It's locked from the outside.
Come on, Dory. You can do it.
Destiny! Destiny! Wall! Wall! Wall!
(DESTINY SCREAMS)
MARLIN: Dory, no! Wait!
DESTINY: Dory!
- Bailey, where are they headed?
- Ooh. I'm losing them.
(DOOR HANDLE CLICKING)
Dory, it's over.
- No, there's got to be a way.
- ALL: Yeah. There's a way!
Dory, now listen to me.
There's no way to get out.
But-- There's got to be a way.
There's always a way.
There isn't, Dory. I'm telling you.
This time there is no other way.
Well, what about that?
Holy carp. There is another way.
(EXHALES) Take a deep breath, kid.
ALL: (CHANTING)
Release! Release! Release!
Release! Release! Release! Release!
♪ Your lying eyes... ♪
(SCREAMING)
CARL: What is that?
DAISY: I don't care what it is!
Get it off!
What the--
Suck it, bipeds.
All right, Hank, you've got seven arms--
I don't know. Just try something.
- Okay. Here we go.
- (HONKING)
- Huh? Hey! Stop. Stop. Wait! No!
- Hey! Hey! Stop. Wait. Oh no!
- That's doing something.
- And we are moving. Good job, Hank.
- Wait, wait, wait! Come on! Whoa!
- Hey! What? Hey! Stop! Wait. Wait.
Listen, I'm not trying to tell you
how to drive. Certainly I can't do--
I'm not in any position--
But could you go faster?
(GRUNTS)
No! No, no! No, no, no!
- (TYRES SCREECHING)
- (GASPS)
- Whoo!
- Hey! Give us our truck back!
I can't see squat.
Which way are we going?
Okay. Well, all the cars
are going left so go left.
Gilman Street. Ashby Avenue. Powell.
Gilman Street again. Huh.
Gilman Street again.
How much longer
are we gonna veer left?
Okay, we just need to know
how we got on,
then we'll know how to get off.
Well, let me know
when you figure it out.
Unfortunately I can't remember
how we got on.
(GASPS) Hey, I know those guys!
That's where we came from. Turn right.
Here we go!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(ALL SCREAM)
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Wait!
- Oh my-- Whoa. Hey!
DAISY: We are so fired.
DORY: Keep straight. Straight. Left.
Left. No, no, no. Right. Right. Right.
- Good driving, Hank.
- Pay attention to the road.
Oh, I'm sorry. Oh. Uh-oh.
Fork in the road.
- Which way?
- Ocean. Ocean. Hey, a boat!
You know, I haven't had
great experiences with boats, but I--
- Which way?
- Boats go to the ocean. Right!
Hold on!
(ALL SCREAM)
We're out of time, kid.
Where do we go now?
Um... Okay, I'll figure it out.
I don't know, but--
Well, something
will come and-- (GASPS)
Seagulls. Hank, follow those birds!
The ocean's left, Hank.
SEAGULLS:
Mine, mine, mine, mine.
Ooh. Hold on. Ooh.
I'm getting something.
Is it them? Is everything perfect?
Uh-oh, it's the fuzz. Busted.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Okay, we're good. The ocean!
It's straight ahead. Floor it!
Now we're talking.
- Oh. Uh-oh!
- What do you mean, "Uh-oh"?
Oh no. What would I do?
What would I do? What would I do?
Hank, I'm gonna ask you
to do something crazy.
I'm okay with crazy.
All right, Hank.
Ooh. There's no way out. It's over.
They're going to fish jail! Ooh!
Wait. Ooh. Oh no. Ooh.
Get back! Incoming!
(DORY AND HANK SCREAMING)
♪ I see trees of green
♪ Red roses too
♪ I see them bloom for me and you
♪ And I think to myself ♪
(ALL CHEERING)
Whoo-hoo!
(SNEEZES)
Fish!
(BOTH GROANING)
(IN SLOW MOTION) Dory!
SIGOURNEY: What lies before you
represents the third
and final part of the...
Marine Life mission.
Rescue, rehabilitation, and release.
Come to Papa.
I'm Sigourney Weaver.
Thank you for joining me.
DORY: One, two, three, four...
Uh...
Wait a minute. Why am I counting?
Hey, where is everyone?
Uh-oh, did they leave me?
No! No, no. They wouldn't do that.
Okay. That's okay. I can figure this out.
What was I just doing then?
I was, um, covering my face,
so I was trying to hide.
Okay, so why was I trying to hide? Wait!
(GASPS) Oh, I-- Five, six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
Ready or not, here I come!
- Ha, found you!
- (LAUGHING)
- I see you!
- Oh!
Haha! Gotcha!
HANK: All right, you little shrimps,
recess is over.
- Aw, man.
- Ah, nobody found me!
Bring it in. Time for another--
Don't touch me.
Time for another lesson.
When is Mr Ray coming back
from his migration?
If he's smart he'll stay away from here
as long as he can.
But until he does,
I'm your substitute teacher.
Okay kids, who wants to learn
about echolocation?
- CHILDREN: Boo.
- Nobody.
DESTINY: Oh, come on, guys.
It's actually really cool.
Okay, kelpcake. Have fun.
Nice day for a swim, huh?
All right. Bye Mom. Bye Dad.
Well, I guess we'll go back home
and brush up on the anemone.
You coming, Dory?
Me? Oh I'm just going to the dropoff.
Oh, okay. What? The dropoff? No!
That's-- That's a good idea?
Yeah. I just thought
I'd go enjoy the view. Bye.
The view. Well, you have a good time!
All by yourself. Not getting lost.
(HUMMING)
(PANTING)
Oh!
Huh?
Oh, no, no, no. No, no.
No, no, Dory. Dory. Dory! D--
- Hey, Marlin.
- Oh, hey. Hello, Dory.
You all right? You look worried.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
It's how I always look.
What?
Well, I just--
(CHUCKLES)
You did it.
(GASPS)
- JENNY: Yay!
- You did it, kelpcake.
- Yes!
- (LAUGHS) Did what?
Sweetie, you just followed the shells
all the way back home.
Oh, my gosh! I did? All by myself?
- Yeah.
- Do you know what this means?
It means you can do
whatever you put your mind to, Dory.
BABY DORY: Really?
(FISH LAUGHING PLAYFULLY)
(GASPS) Mommy,
can I go play with them?
- Yes.
- Absolutely! Go get them, kelpcake.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah. I did it.
- Hmm.
It really is quite a view.
Yep.
Unforgettable.
♪ Unforgettable
♪ That's what you are
♪ Tho' near or far
♪ Like a song of love that clings to me
♪ How the thought of you
does things to me
♪ Never before
♪ Has someone been more...
♪ Unforgettable
♪ In every way
♪ And forever more
♪ That's how you'll stay
♪ That's why, darling, it's incredible
♪ That someone so unforgettable
(WARBLES)
(SQUAWKS)
♪ Thinks that I am
♪ Unforgettable, too
♪ Unforgettable
♪ In every way
♪ And forever more
♪ That's how you'll stay
♪ That's why, darling, it's incredible
♪ That someone so unforgettable
♪ Thinks that I am
♪ Unforgettable, too ♪
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
BOTH: Off, off, off, off, off,
off, off, off, off, off!
(BLOAT PANTING)
BLOAT: Come on. Roll, roll.
That's it. Hurry!
That's it. Just roll!
PEACH: I'm right behind you.
GILL: You can do it!
Just a little farther. That's it!
GURGLE: I am truly going to vomit!
- JACQUES: Voilà!
- All right, gang, good work.
(ALL CHEERING)
Look, Flo, we made it!
We won't have any more problems
from here on out.
(ALL GASP)
No respect for ocean life.
BLOAT: Now what?
(YAWNING)
(SNICKERING)